Guide to the David Newton Henderson Papers, 1930-1976 RL.00528
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Speeches Series
  - 1973-1974 (Box 324)
  - 1975 (Box 325)
- Subject Files Series
  The largest and most diverse category in the Henderson Papers, the Subject Files contain correspondence and printed material concerning a wide range of subjects and legislative items. They include much public opinion on current legislation arranged both under the name of the issue itself (e.g. Gun Control) and under the name of the standing committee through which the legislation passed (e.g. Judiciary). There is similar material under Gun Control and Judiciary so both subject and committee listing should be checked. There is also much material on general subjects and administrative matters.
  Notations have been made about the contents of some files. These notations are designed as an aid, not as a complete list of contents.
  - Abortion, 1971, 1976.See also Judiciary. (Box 326)
  - Aging, Select Committee on, 1975 (Box 326)
  - Agriculture, 1961-1964 (Box 326)
    Major issues in entire subject include: 1961: Omnibus Farm Bill; 1962: Food and Agriculture Act; 1963: Mexican Farm Labor Bill; 1965: Omnibus Farm Bill (especially cotton proposals); 1966: legislation to establish separate banks for loans to rural electric cooperatives; 1969: Agricultural Marketing and Bargaining Act, Agricultural Appropriations Bill; 1970: Family Nutrition Act (food stamp reform); 1971: Farm Credit Act, National Agricultural Marketing and Bargaining Act; 1972: legislation to deny food stamps to strikers; 1973: food stamps for strikers, budget reductions in Soil Conservation and Rural Environment programs; 1975: Food Stamp Reform Act; see also Federal and State Agencies. Agriculture, Department of.
  - Agriculture, 1965-May, 1967 (Box 327)
  - Agriculture, June, 1967-1970 (Box 328)
  - Agriculture, 1971-1975 (Box 329)
  - Agriculture, 1975 (Box 330)
  - Aid to Depressed Areas, 1961 (Box 330)
  - Airports, 1960-1963 (Box 330)
  - Alaska Pipeline, 1973 (Box 330)
  - Americans for Constitutional Action, 1968, 1972 (Box 330)
  - American Public Welfare Association, 1967 (Box 330)
  - American Society for Public Administration, 1964-1965 (Box 330)
  - Amnesty, 1974-1975.See also Armed Services, 1973. (Box 330)
  - Anti-Ballistic Missile System, 1969 (Box 330)
  - Appointments, 1963-1972 (Box 331)
  - Appointments, 1973-1976 (Box 332)
  - Appreciation, 1967-1968 (Box 332)
  - Appropriations, 1961-1969 (Box 332)
    This category includes: 1971: educational appropriations; 1972: Emergency School Assistance Act, food stamps for strikers; 1973: school lunch programs, bombing of Cambodia, aid to North Vietnam; 1974: Emergency School Assistance Act; 1975: override of presidential veto of education appropriations.
  - Appropriations, 1970-1972 (Box 333)
  - Appropriations, 1973-1974 (Box 334)
  - Appropriations, 1975-1976 (Box 335)
  - Armed Services, 1961-1968 (Box 336)
    This category includes: 1963: Military Pay Bill; 1969: Recomputation Bill; 1971: Nedzi-Whalen Amendment to set a withdrawal date for U.S. involvement in Vietnam, Draft Law Reform Bill; 1973: amnesty.
  - Armed Services, 1969-1975 (Box 337)
  - Associations ' Representatives, 1966 (Box 337)
  - Atlantic Union Resolution, 1976 (Box 337)
  - Banking and Currency, 1961-1968 (Box 338)
    1961: financing of home loans and public housing projects; 1968: Riot Insurance bills, Omnibus Housing Bill, Federal Savings Institutions Act; 1969: One-Bank Holding Bill; 1973-1974: wage and price controls; 1975: financial crisis of New York City, Housing Bill.
  - Banking and Currency, 1969-1973 (Box 339)
  - Banking and Currency, 1974-1975 (Box 340)
  - Basic Adult Education Program, 1967 (Box 340)
  - Biography, 1965-1975 (Box 340)
  - Bolling Report, 1974Report of the Bolling Committee on proposed reorganization of the House committee structure (Box 341)
  - Bombing Range, 1961-1964 (Box 341)
    Concerns controversy over purchase of land by the Air Force to be used for a bombing range and the possible effects on wildlife and stock production
  - Broiler Industry, 1961-1962 (Box 341)
  - Budget, 1975-1976 (Box 342)
  - Budget Committee (Proposed), 1973-1974 (Box 342)
  - Busing, 1972 see also Civil Rights, Judiciary. (Box 342)
  - Campus Unrest, 1969-1971 (Box 342)
  - Carolina Power and Light Company, 1962 (Box 342)
  - Census, 1961-1966See also Federal and State Agencies. Census, Bureau of. (Box 342)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the United States, 1963 (Box 342)
  - Chambers of Commerce, 1961-1966 (Box 342)
  - Cherry Blossom Festival, 1962-1963, 1966 (Box 342)
  - Child Care and the Family, 1975-1976Concerns the Child and Family Service Act. (Box 343)
  - China, 1972 (Box 343)
  - Christmas Cards, 1975 (Box 343)
  - Civil Aeronautics, 1961-1965 (Box 343)
  - Civil Air Patrol, 1964 (Box 343)
  - Civil Defense, 1961 (Box 343)
  - Civil Defense, 1962-1966 (Box 344)
  - Civil Rights, 1962-1964 (Box 344)
    1963-1964: Kennedy- Johnson administrations' civil rights proposals; 1968: Poor People's March on Washington, assassination of Martin Luther King; 1969-1972: busing to achieve school integration; see also Poor People's March on Washington, Busing, School Crisis, Segregation.
  - Civil Rights, 1965-1972 (Box 345)
  - Civil Rights. Activities in Third District, 1964 (Box 345)
    Concerns controversy between the U.S. Department of Defense and local residents over the implementation of the Gesell Report. The Report called for integrated facilities for use of servicemen in communities adjacent to military complexes. If compliance to this request did not occur, the report directed military officials to declare the local communities off-limits to base personnel thus disrupting local economies.
  - Civil Rights. Open Housing Bill, 1968 (Box 345)
  - Civil Rights. Special, 1964Contains proposed amendments to the Civil Rights Bill. (Box 345)
  - Classified Advertising Fraud, 1968 (Box 345)
    In 1968 many merchants and businessmen in Goldsboro, N.C., received solicitations for classified advertising under the guise of renewing yellow page advertisements. Henderson asked that these be sent to him for use in governmental action against the solicitors.
  - Clay Products Industry, 1961 (Box 345)
  - Clerk of the House, 1971-1972, 1974-1976Contains accounts of Henderson's office expenses. (Box 345)
  - Close-Up Program, 1975-1976 (Box 346)
  - Colleagues, 1960-1969 (Box 346)
  - Colleagues, 1970-1976 (Box 347)
  - Collection of Debts, 1965-1976 (Box 348)
  - Communism, 1961-1969See also Cuba, Internal Security, Un-American Activities. (Box 348)
  - Complaints, 1973-1975 (Box 348)
  - Condolences, 1968 (Box 349)
  - Congratulations, 1968 (Box 349)
  - Congressional Operations, Joint Committee on, 1975 (Box 349)
  - Congressional Record Remarks, 1961-1976and undated (Box 349)
  - Consumer Protection Agency, 1975Concerns legislation to create this agency. (Box 349)
  - Cotton, 1961-1966 (Box 349)
  - Crime, 1969-1970 (Box 349)
  - Crackpots, 1961-1976 (Box 350)
  - Cuba, 1961-1963 (Box 350)
  - Daylight Savings Time, 1974 (Box 351)
  - Democratic Caucus, 1973-1976 (Box 351)
  - Democratic National and State Committees, 1960-1964 (Box 351)
  - Democratic Party (National), 1967-1976 (Box 351)
  - Democratic Party (State), 1962-1976 (Box 352)
  - Democratic Research Organization, 1975 (Box 353)
  - Democratic Study Group, 1969? (Box 353)
  - Deposit Insurance, 1974 (Box 353)
  - Direct VA Loans, 1961-1966 (Box 353)
  - District of Columbia, 1961-1975 (Box 353)
  - District Office, 1961-1975 (Box 353)
  - Draftees, 1966-1971 (Box 353)
    Correspondence from constituents requesting deferment or reclassification. See also Federal and State Agencies. Selective Service System.
  - Drug Abuse, 1971-1973 (Box 353)
  - Dual Compensation, 1963 (Box 353)
  - Economy, 1971-1976 (Box 353)
  - Education and Labor, 1961-1963 (Box 354)
    1961: minimum wage legislation, Presidential Reorganization Plan No. 5 (to expedite decision making in cases coming before the National Labor Review Board); 1962: legislation concerning unemployment compensation, equal pay for equal work, and federal aid to education; 1963: Vocational Education Act, legislation to include fringe benefits in wage predeterminations issued under the Davis-Bacon Act of 1931; 1964: Economic Opportunity Act, minimum wage and overtime legislation, aid to education in areas of English and industrial education; 1965-1966: Fair Labor Standard Act amendments (to extend the minimum wage to more classes of workers); 1966-1967: Common Situs Picketing Bill; 1968: Occupational Safety and Health Act, Arts and Humanities Bill, agricultural unionization legislation; 1969: legislation extending the Economic Opportunity Act, student loans; 1970: Sikes-Steiger Occupational Health and Safety Bill; 1970-1971: Equal Employment Opportunity Enforcement Act; 1971: National Right to Work Law; 1972: termination of Emergency School Assistance Program, higher education legislation, minimum wage; 1973: Labor-Management Bill (giving federal employees the right to strike), school lunch programs, Vocational Rehabilitation Bill; 1974: Emergency School Aid Act, Rehabilitation Act Amendment, Career Opportunities Program, minimum wage for domestic employees; 1975: minimum wage, common situs picketing, cutbacks in aid to education, HEW regulations involving equal distribution of athletic scholarships between males and females; see also Federal Aid to Education, Public Law 874, Minimum Wage.
  - Education and Labor, 1964-1965 (Box 355)
  - Education and Labor, 1966-1968 (Box 356)
  - Education and Labor, 1969-1970 (Box 357)
  - Education and Labor, 1971-June, 1972 (Box 358)
  - Education and Labor, July, 1972-1973 (Box 359)
  - Education and Labor, 1974-1976 (Box 360)
  - Education and Labor. Taft-Hartley Act, Jan.-June, 1965 (Box 361)
    Concerns controversial proposal to repeal section 146 of the Taft-Hartley Act, authorizing states to enact right to work laws.
  - Education and Labor. Taft-Hartley Act, July, 1965-1966 (Box 362)
  - Educational Television, 1962 (Box 362)
  - Energy Crisis, 1973see also Federal and State Agencies. Newspaper Questionnaire; Oil and Gas, Office of. (Box 362)
  - Energy Crisis, 1974-March, 1975 (Box 363)
  - Energy Crisis, April, 1975-1976 (Box 364)
  - Environment, 1971-1975 (Box 364)
  - Environmental Health Center, Research Triangle Park, N.C., 1962 (Box 364)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1975see also Judiciary (Box 364)
  - Estate Tax Exemption, 1976 (Box 364)
  - European Tour, 1971 (Box 365)
  - Excise Tax, 1961 (Box 365)
  - Federal Aid to Education, 1960-1961 See also Education and Labor, Appropriations. (Box 366)
  - Federal Aid to Education, 1962-1963 (Box 367)
  - Federal Election Campaign Laws, 1975 (Box 367)
  - Federal Grants to North Carolina, 1966-1971 (Box 367)
  - Federal Pay Increase, 1974 see also Committee Files. Post Office and Civil Service. (Box 367)
  - Feed Grain Programs, 1962-1963 (Box 367)
  - Financial Reform, 1976 (Box 367)
  - Fish and Wildlife, 1970 (Box 367)
  - Fisheries, 1961-1966 (Box 367)
  - Fishing Industry, 1970-1971 (Box 367)
  - Food Fermentation Center, 1962 (Box 367)
  - Foreign Affairs, 1961 (Box 367)
    1961-1972: foreign aid; 1975: Kissinger's Mid-East negotiations, Greek-Turkish war over Cyprus, military aid to South Vietnam
  - Foreign Affairs, 1962-1975 (Box 368)
  - General Information Requests, 1975 (Box 369)
  - Government Operations, 1961-1975 (Box 369)
  - Guestbook (Box 369)
  - Gun Control, 1965-c.1968See also Judiciary (Box 369)
  - Gun Control Legislation, 1968, June-Dec.; 1976 (Box 370)
  - Hall of Fame, 1959-1966 (Box 370)
  - Health Care, 1975 (Box 370)
  - HEW Appropriation Veto, 1970 (Box 371)
  - Highways, 1961, 1965-1966See also Committee Files. Public Works. Surface Transportation and Transportation, Subcommittees on. (Box 371)
  - Hill-Burton Hospital Construction Program, 1971 (Box 371)
  - House Administration, 1961-1975 (Box 371)
  - Housing, 1961-1966 (Box 371)
  - Hurricanes, 1960-1962 (Box 371)
  - Impacted Area School Aid Program, 1973 (Box 372)
  - Impeachment, 1973-March, 1974Concerns the Watergate affair and impeachment proceedings against Richard Nixon. (Box 372)
  - Impeachment, April-December, 1974 (Box 373)
  - Impeachment of William O. Douglas, 1970 (Box 373)
  - Imports and Exports, 1962-1965 (Box 373)
  - Inauguration, 1961, 1968-1969 (Box 373)
  - Inflation, 1961-1973See also Federal and State Agencies. Cost of Living Council; Management and Budget, Office of. (Box 373)
  - Inflation, 1974-1976 (Box 374)
  - Insurance Plans for the Aged, 1962see also Medicare (Box 374)
  - Interior and Insular Affairs, 1961-1975 (Box 375)
    1974: federal land use legislation
  - Internal Security, 1970-1975See also Un-American Activities (Box 376)
  - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1961-May, 1963 (Box 376)
    1961-1962: legislation restricting railway freight rates; 1963: legislation to reduce compulsory minimum rates for the trucking industry; 1969: Railroad Retirement amendments, pay television; 1970: Political Broadcast Bill; 1971: legislation to prohibit the broadcasting of advertisements for alcoholic beverages, citation of CBS and its president Frank Stanton for contempt of Congress after failing to comply with a subpoena issued by the Subcommittee on Investigations, railway regulation reform, funding for the Supersonic Jet; 1972: Airport Development Acceleration Act, legislation to prohibit the use of the telephone in the collection of debts; 1973: Amendment to the Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to regulate the sale of vitamins and mineral substances; 1974: Older Americans Act, no fault automobile insurance; 1975: sale of vitamins and food supplements
  - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, June, 1963-1969 (Box 377)
  - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1970-1971 (Box 378)
  - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1972-1973 (Box 379)
  - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1974 (Box 380)
  - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1975 (Box 381)
  - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinners, 1961-1966 (Box 382)
  - Job Applicants, 1971-May, 1975see also Summer Employment (Box 382)
  - Job Applicants, 1976 (Box 383)
  - Judiciary, 1961-March, 1964 (Box 383)
    1963-1975: legislation to restore prayer and Bible reading in the public schools, gun control; 1965: Voting Act (authorizing federal examiners to register qualified voters and suspend devices such as literacy tests); 1966: Fair Housing Provision of the Civil Rights Act; 1967: Monday Holiday Bill; 1968: Open Housing Bill; 1968-1971: legislation to lower the voting age to 18; 1970: TIAA-CREF Retirement Program; 1970-1971: Equal Rights Amendment; 1971: busing; 1973-1974: abortion legislation; 1974: confirmation of Nelson Rockefeller as Vice President; see also Equal Rights Amendment, Gun Control, Abortion
  - Judiciary, April, 1964-July, 1967 (Box 384)
  - Judiciary, August, 1967-August, 1971 (Box 385)
  - Judiciary, September, 1971-1974 (Box 386)
  - Judiciary, 1975 (Box 387)
  - Judiciary. Busing of Students to Achieve Racial Balance, 1970 (Box 387)
  - Judiciary. Prayer in Schools, 1969 (Box 387)
  - Ku Klux Klan Hearings, 1966 (Box 387)
  - Labor Unions, 1963 (Box 388)
  - Libraries, 1964-1971 (Box 388)
  - Lists, Miscellaneous, 1959-1969 (Box 388)
    Contains lists of various political, social or occupational groups in the Third District eg. teachers, veterans club members, young Democrats
  - Lumber Industry, 1962-1967 (Box 388)
  - Lumber Industry, 1968-1972 (Box 389)
  - Maps, 1963 (Box 389)
  - Media, 1972-1976See also Press, Radio and TV, Recording Studio (Box 389)
  - Medicare, Jan.-April, 1962 see also Insurance Plans for the Aged. (Box 389)
  - Medicare, May, 1962-1964 (Box 390)
  - Medicare, 1965-1966 (Box 391)
  - Menhaden Industry, 1962 (Box 391)
  - Merchant Marines and Fisheries, 1961-1975 (Box 391)
  - Methyl Bromide, 1968-1969 (Box 392)
  - Middle East, 1967, 1969-1970, 1973-1975 (Box 392)
  - Military Pay Allotments, 1965-1969 (Box 392)
  - Military Promotions, 1966-1969 (Box 392)
  - Military Reassignment, 1966-1970 (Box 392)
  - Minimum Wage, Jan.-March, 1961 see also Education and Labor. (Box 392)
  - Minimum Wage, April, 1961-1966 (Box 393)
  - Mosquito Control, 1961-1970 (Box 393)
  - Motorcycle Industry, 1974 (Box 393)
  - National Education Association, 1961 (Box 393)
  - National Federation of Independent Business, 1961-April, 1962 (Box 393)
    Contains ballots sent by members of this organization expressing their opinion on current legislation.
  - National Federation of Independent Business, May, 1962-1970 (Box 394)
  - National Federation of Independent Business, 1971-1975 (Box 395)
  - National Fisheries Institute, 1963-1964 (Box 395)
  - National Guard, 1961-1963 (Box 395)
  - National Parks, 1961-1966 (Box 395)
  - Newsletters, 1961Newsletters sent to Henderson's office by various organizations. (Box 395)
  - Newspaper Questionnaires, 1974In March, 1974,Henderson asked Third District newspapers to print a questionnaire concerning the gas shortage. (Box 395)
  - Newspapers and Magazines, 1960-1965 (Box 396)
  - No-Fault Insurance, 1974 (Box 396)
  - North Carolina, 1961-1967, 1975 (Box 396)
  - North Carolina Democratic Club of Washington, D.C., 1961-1962 (Box 396)
  - North Carolina Democratic Club of Washington, D.C., 1963-1975 (Box 397)
  - North Carolina State University, 1969 (Box 397)
  - Nuclear Testing, 1961-1962 (Box 397)
  - Patronage, 1966-1976 (Box 397)
  - Peanuts, 1962-1963 (Box 397)
  - Pension Reform, 1974 see also Ways and Means. (Box 397)
  - Personal, 1964-1965, 1974-1976 (Box 397)
  - Personal. Financial Statements, 1962, 1965, 1969-1971 (Box 398)
  - Personnel, 1961-1976 (Box 398)
  - Photographs, 1964-1974Most are undated. (Box 398)
  - Pickle Industry, 1962-1964 (Box 399)
  - Plywood, 1961-1966 (Box 399)
  - Political and Personal Political, A-R (Box 399)
  - Political and Personal Political, S-Z (Box 400)
  - Poll Monthly, 1971-1973 (Box 400)
    Results and analyses of a monthly poll of public opinion in North Carolina on current issues conducted by W. H. Long Marketing, Inc. of Greensboro.
  - Pollution, 1970 (Box 400)
  - Poor People's March on Washington, 1968 see also Civil Rights. 1968 (Box 400)
  - Pornography, 1969-1974See also Federal and State Agencies. Post Office Department (Box 400)
  - Potatoes, 1962-1963 (Box 400)
  - Poultry, 1961-1963See also Turkeys (Box 400)
  - Poverty Programs, 1965-1969 (Box 401)
  - Press. Radio and TV, 1961-1971, 1975 see also Media, Recording Studio (Box 401)
  - Prisoners of War Information, 1973 (Box 402)
  - Public Law 874, 1950-1969P.L. 874 provided for financial assistance to schools in federally affected areas such as near military bases. (Box 402)
  - Public Works, 1961-1962Henderson became a member of this committee in 1963.Material for 1963-1976is in Committee Files. (Box 403)
  - Questionnaires, 1970-1973 (Box 403)
  - Questionnaires. Comments, 1973, 1975 (Box 403)
  - Questionnaires. Preparation, Results, and Analyses, 1973 (Box 403)
  - Questionnaires. Requiring a Response, 1973 (Box 404)
  - Questionnaires. Requiring no Response, 1973 (Box 405)
  - Railroads, 1963, 1971 see also Interstate and Foreign Commerce (Box 405)
  - Recommendations, 1961-1967 (Box 406)
  - Recommendations, 1968-1972 (Box 407)
  - Recommendations, 1973-1976 (Box 408)
  - Recommendations. Students, 1961-1963 (Box 409)
  - Recording Studio, 1969-1970, 1975 (Box 409)
  - Redistricting, 1961, 1970-1971 (Box 409)
  - Referrals, 1961-1974 (Box 409)
  - Referrals, 1975-1976 (Box 410)
  - Refrigerated Containers, 1961 (Box 410)
  - Reorganization Plan, 1962 (Box 410)
    Concerns Henderson's vote against President Kennedy's proposal to establish a Department of Urban Affairs and Housing
  - Revenue Sharing, 1971-1973See also Ways and Means (Box 410)
  - Riots, 1965-1969 (Box 410)
  - Rules, Jan.-July, 1961 (Box 410)
    1961: Concerns controversial resolution sponsored by House Speaker Sam Rayburn to increase the membership of the Rules Committee
  - Rules, 1963-1975 (Box 411)
  - School Bus Safety, 1973 (Box 411)
  - School Crisis, 1970 (Box 411)
    Contains agenda of N.C. delegation meeting regarding school integration, and a collection of bills and resolutions from 1969-1970 dealing with schools and civil rights.
  - School Lunch Program, 1971 see also Education and Labor (Box 411)
  - Science and Astronautics, 1973-1974 (Box 411)
  - Science and Technology, 1975 (Box 411)
  - Segregation, 1960-1962See also Civil Rights (Box 411)
  - Service Station Operators, 1976 (Box 411)
  - Social Security, 1960-1966See also Ways and Means; Federal and State Agencies. Social Security Administration (Box 412)
  - Soil and Water Conservation, 1961-1966, 1976 (Box 412)
  - Sole-Surviving Son, 1966-1969 (Box 412)
    Concerns requests for military transfer from war zones on the basis that one's brother was killed in combat.
  - Southeast Asia, Jan.-May, 1970 (Box 412)
    1970: reflects military incursions into Cambodia and Laos, student march on Washington, Kent State incident; 1970-1971: legislation to withdraw U.S. troops from Southeast Asia; 1971: court martial of William Calley; 1972: prisoners of war, bombing of North Vietnam; 1973: bombing of Cambodia, Paris Peace Settlement and proposed economic aid to North Vietnam; 1974-1975: missing-in-action personnel; 1975: Mayaguez incident, Vietnamese refugees, continuing aid to South Vietnam; see also Armed Services, Sole-Surviving Son, Prisoners of War Information, Draftees; for material before 1970 see Vietnam
  - Southeast Asia, June, 1970-1974 (Box 413)
  - Southeast Asia, 1975-1976 (Box 414)
  - Space and Astronautics, 1962 (Box 414)
  - Standards of Official Conduct, 1975 (Box 414)
  - Stationery Account, 1961-1964 (Box 414)
  - Student Loans, 1961-1968 (Box 414)
  - Student Loans, 1969-1971 (Box 415)
  - Student Survey, 1972 (Box 415)
  - Summer Employment, 1962-1976See also Job Applicants (Box 415)
  - Surplus Property, 1961-1967 (Box 415)
  - Tariffs, 1961-1962 (Box 416)
  - Telephone-Telegraph Account, 1961-1976 (Box 416)
  - Telephone Message Books, 1970-1971, undated (Box 416)
  - Telephone Message Books, undated (Box 417)
  - Textiles, 1961-1968 (Box 417)
  - Textiles, 1969-1975 (Box 418)
  - Tobacco, 1960-1965 (Box 418)
    1965: Acreage-Poundage Program; 1969: controversy over Federal Trade Commission regulations requiring radio and TV stations to provide free time for anti-smoking advertisements and to prohibit the advertising of cigarettes on radio and TV
  - Tobacco, 1966-1972 (Box 419)
  - Tobacco, 1973-1976 (Box 420)
  - Tobacco. Dear Colleague Letter Regarding Distortion of Truth About, 1973 (Box 420)
  - Tobacco. Use of MH-30, 1960-1963 (Box 420)
  - Tobacco in the Philippines, 1962 (Box 420)
  - Treasurer of the North Carolina Delegation, 1965-1970 (Box 421)
  - Truman, Harry, 1967 (Box 421)
  - Turkeys, 1962-1963See also Poultry (Box 421)
  - Un-American Activities, 1961-1969See also Internal Security (Box 421)
  - United Nations, 1962-1966, 1969-1975 (Box 421)
  - U.S. News and World Report Interview, 1976 (Box 421)
  - Veterans Affairs, 1960-1962See also Direct VA Loans; Federal and State Agencies. Veterans Administration. (Box 421)
  - Veterans Affairs, 1963-1969 (Box 422)
  - Veterans Affairs, 1970-1974 (Box 423)
  - Veterans Affairs, 1975-1976 (Box 424)
  - Vietnam, 1965-1969See also Southeast Asia (for material from 1970-1976),Armed Services, Draftees, Sole-Surviving Son. (Box 424)
  - Vietnam. Speech Material, 1966 (Box 424)
  - Voting Record Comments, 1970, 1973 (Box 424)
  - Voting Rights, 1969-1970See also Judiciary (Box 424)
  - Water Pollution Control, 1961-1963 (Box 425)
  - Ways and Means, 1961-March, 1962 (Box 425)